Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajput.
I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years. I am an
MBA in Finance and
today I am presenting to you
Reliance 1 Life Insurance, a guaranteed
safe plan named Super
Assured Future Endowment Plan. Here
you will get the most lump sum guaranteed maturity.
This plan you are watching is the channel of Anil
Rajpat Triple FS,
where you get
information about different plans of different companies at one place
and you will find the maximum number of insurance
videos of different plans of different companies on
this channel. If you have come to this channel for the
first time, then definitely subscribe to this channel
where you will
get 300 plus videos related to insurance which will
help you in your financial planning.
Talking about the eligibility criteria of this plan,
here a child from 1 year to a
person of 55 years can
purchase this policy. The minimum premium
in this is ₹5000000
which you can
buy on annual mode, quarterly mode or monthly.  You can take it on annual mode or semi-annual mode. If we
talk about the premium payment term here, then you will get the option of 5 years, 7 years, 8 years, 10 years and
12 years and if
you want to take maturity then the option of maturity is given in the 15th year, 16th year, 20th year
or 21st year. The
option of regular premium payment is not given here,
you can purchase this policy only in limited pay.
In this plan, you will get
Sum Assured on Maturity,
Accrued Guaranteed Edition and Accrued Guaranteed
Loyalty Edition as maturity. Sum Assured on
Maturity will mean Basic Sum
Assured.
I will tell you in details in the benefit illustration.
You will get Guaranteed Edition every year
in this policy which will keep accruing and will keep
accumulating. It does not mean that
it is declared and will come to your account. This will
not happen, it will keep accumulating. There
is a Basic Sum Assured. Base Sum
Assured or which is also called Sum Assured and Maturity has a  There will be a
certain percentage. Suppose
you take a policy term for 20 years, then for the
first 5 years you will get the sum assured maturity
at 1, which will keep accumulating, then for the
next 5 years it will be added at 3,
then for the next 5 years it will be added at 5 and
in the last 5 years you will get it at 7.
A certain percentage of the sum assured maturity or base sum, which has been mentioned
here, will keep accumulating
and at the end of the policy
in the last year, you will get it as maturity.
You will also get a
Guaranteed Loyalty Addition. For example,
if you pay premium for 10 years, then it will
start after 5 years on
different premium payments. You
can see in the tables here when
you will start getting GL. So, suppose you are
paying premium for 10 years, from the fifth year
you will start getting how much % of whose sum
assured and maturity, this will also get accumulated,
your cash will
not come in your account in cash, this will also keep getting accumulated.  It will go
and you will get it on maturity in the
last year of the policy. Settlement option: When
maturity is approaching you, you will have an
option to inform the company 30 days in advance
and you want to tell
that this maturity amount is coming to me all at once, for
example, if ₹1 lakh is coming
then I do not want the entire 20 lakhs at once,
I want to take it as income.
This income should be minimum ₹000 for the next 5, 10 or 15 years. If it is
less than this then
you will have to take the lump sum amount at once.
Another option will be seen in this that instead of
taking the entire 20 lakhs at once, suppose you
took ₹1 lakh for maturity and for the remaining 10
lakhs, for example, you took income. In
this way, you can take different amounts for one
maturity and can
also take the income option. Here, if the
rate of interest in the year when your maturity is approaching is less than 4.30 then you can go for
settlement.  You will not be able to take the option of this. You will have to
take the lump sum amount only, but if the
rate is more than this, then you can take the option,
but at the time when the settlement period is going on,
your insurance cover will not be valid,
you will not be able to surrender at that time and
you will not get the loan facility during the settlement option.
Benefit Death benefit includes
higher of sum on death or 105% of
total premium paid, whichever is higher of these two will be
given. What is the definition of sum due?
You will get death benefit by adding 11 times the annual premium or base sum assured plus Amount Guaranteed Addition plus Amount Guaranteed Loyalty Addition.
Now, if you are taking this policy
for a minor,
purchasing the policy for a child, you are
taking the policy for a minor whose age is 8 years, then
his insurance cover will start from the first day,
but if the child is less than 8 years of age, then
his insurance cover will start after he turns 8 years of age or after minimum two policy terms are completed,
but suppose his age is less than 8 years.  If the
policy is for only one year and the child dies during that time, then
you will
get only the total premium paid back and not the insurance cover.
Now let us understand the
Super Ayur Future and Doman
Safe plan of La Nippon Life Insurance with the benefit illustration.
Here is a 35 year old person
named Anil Rajput who is
paying premium for 10 years and
wants to take maturity in the 20th year for which
he is paying an annual premium of ₹ lakh.
Here he is paying a
premium of ₹ lakh for the base cover. He is also purchasing accidental cover
and disability cover for a premium of ₹ 1460.
He is
also purchasing a critical illness cover of ₹ 10 lakh for a premium of ₹ 4229.
So I have also added the ad here. The
base semester here will be ₹
54836. This is very important.
This will be used in all the calculations, which is
also called sum headed and maturity, from the first day.  The
first benefit will be of 11 lakhs and
with riders etc. your first year
premium will be ₹11213 with GST
and from the second year it will be
8962. Now here you see that one lakh
customers are paying premium for 10 years
and the first option they are getting is
called Accru Guaranteed Addition
which is
9548 as I had mentioned in the table, in the first
year you get 1 per basic cess,
base cess is ₹
54000, so its 1 per becomes
9548, then it will become 9548 in the next year also, so after
adding it the total becomes 1997, then if we add 9548 then it will become
28645, then if we add more to it then it will become 38000, then
47000, then from the fifth year you
get 3 per cess i.e. around 28000, if we add 47000 for
28000 then  76000 then add 28000
then add 28000 and by the 2nd year you have
deposited up to 1900, after 11 years you will get it at 5
i.e. it will become around 47000 more, so 19000
plus 47000 then 28 plus 47000 so this will remain and from
16th year you will get it at 7 which will be
around 63000 so you
can add it here so finally by the time you reach 20th year
your 763
8 69 crude guaranteed addition has been deposited
I will repeat it to you it will start from 9000
it will not come in your account immediately
it will keep getting deposited and after 20 years you will
get how much 7
6369 secondly you get crude guaranteed loyalty
addition because if the premium payment is for
10 years then it will start from the fifth year, from the
fifth year how much % has it become ₹  The
base sum of Rs 54000 is Rs
2871, then multiply it by 23 times 23, it will be Rs 47000,
then add Rs 23000 and it will be Rs 71000,
similarly it will keep increasing to Rs 381,
you will get it at the end of the policy, this Rs 000 will
not be deposited in your account every year, it will keep getting deposited
in the policy and
you will get it at the end of the policy, it will not come in your account, it is getting
deposited in the policy from the fifth year and you will get it after 20 years,
then what do you get on maturity, you
can see here,
in maturity benefit match benefit you
get three things, G Guaranteed Addition, GL
Guaranteed Loyalty Addition Plus Sum S and
Maturity Sum SA, how much is the maturity amount
954836, now see here,
763869, 381935, 954836, if you add these three
then you will get Rs 1640 on maturity  You will
get lakhs of rupees in simple words,
you paid for 10 years, in the 20th year you
got ₹1640, in the meantime you will not get any money
as income, if any
agent or online call you and tells you
that you will get 21 lakhs in your account,
954000 will also come, 81000 will also come, 763000 will also
come and this 9000 will keep getting deposited in your account every year,
23000 will also keep getting deposited to you,
so remember the dialogue of PK movie,
watch PK movie, Aamir Khan's Rang
number is Rang number,
2640 is going to come in your account, all this will not come in your account
together, in different ways,
plus your insurance cover will be of 11 lakhs
which will keep increasing till you get 2155.94, there will be
surrender benefit as well, there will be special
surrender benefit,
you can also take loan up to % of surrender value here, if we
talk about riders then here  You will
get four riders - Accident Death Rider,
Disabilities Rider, Disabilities Plus
Rider and 25 Critical Illness Rider.
Suppose there is death due to an accident, then you will get the amount
of rider you have taken
plus natural cover.
If you have taken Accident Death and Disability Rider, if
you become disabled
and suppose you have an insurance of Rs. 10 lakh, then
you will get income in equal installments of Rs. 10 lakh every year
for the next 10 years and your
policy will continue because death has not occurred.
But if you have taken the third rider
where Disabilities Plus option is given, then
you will get income on disability
but future premium increases are
also waived and in critical illness,
you
can avail critical illness benefit ranging from Rs. 1 lakh to Rs. 50 lakh.
In this, 25 major critical illnesses like cancer and
heart attack are covered. Regarding
other benefits and features of the policy, here you will
save up to Rs. 5 lakh in income tax rate ATC and you will get tax benefit.  You get this and the
income you get through Income Tax in 1010D on maturity will be tax free
if your premium is Rs 5 lakh or less.
Talking about loan, here
you can take loan up to 70% of the surrender value.
You are also given grace period and free
look period in this policy. In this 30 day
policy, you are also given reduced paid up and surrender
benefit. If you have
paid the minimum premium for one year,
you will get a revival period of 5 years in this policy. If for
some reason you have not paid the premium, then
during 5 years you can continue the policy again by paying the late fee and the remaining
premium. So
finally, if I were to review this plan, then it is
a good plan, it is a guaranteed
plan where you are given different premium
payment terms and policy terms. You are
also getting guaranteed addition, loyalty
addition, insurance cover and
tax free income. But
almost every company has this type of plan today,
so think once before purchasing the policy.  Do
compare that if I
am paying premium then I will
get more maturity in it because the maturity
amount is 100% guaranteed, so the
plan of the company which gives more maturity can be a better
option for you,
plus there is a little loop hole in this plan
that there is no waiver and premium
rider here, if you
take a policy for a child and the proposer dies then the
premium increase is not waived
because this rider
is not available in this policy, so if you
want to purchase this policy from me then you can contact me
on whatsapp2, if you want to consult and compare and
purchase the policy then also you
can contact me, if you liked the video then while leaving